<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Josh Armitage</title>
    <link>https://josharmi.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Josh Armitage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://josharmi.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable DNS with EventBridge</title>
      <link>https://josharmi.github.io/posts/scalable-dns-with-eventbridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josharmi.github.io/posts/scalable-dns-with-eventbridge/</guid>
      <description>The Problem DNS, the source of all network problems, can be frustrating to implement at scale. Helpfully, AWS have released this guide on doing multi-account DNS. As with most things multi-account, automating the process is more involved than we would like, nevertheless we persevere and in this case show how AWS EventBridge can be the glue by which we stick together infrastructure at scale.
The Outcome By the end of this you should have:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Security</title>
      <link>https://josharmi.github.io/posts/scaling-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josharmi.github.io/posts/scaling-security/</guid>
      <description>The Scene You&amp;rsquo;re a new CISO at a rapidly scaling technology company with 50 engineers, looking to double engineering within 12 months. The company is trying to maintain its agility and rapid delivery, but you&amp;rsquo;re hitting a point where the security cowboy nature has presented too great a risk to be ignored any longer.
Tasked with imporving the security posture across the board, you&amp;rsquo;re worried that the developers and product owners don&amp;rsquo;t care about security.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIY StackSets with Step Functions</title>
      <link>https://josharmi.github.io/posts/diy-stacksets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josharmi.github.io/posts/diy-stacksets/</guid>
      <description>DIY StackSets with Step Functions Why Recreate StackSets Currently in order to leverage StackSets in any way you need fairly substantial permissions in the target account, as per the documentation, the minimum permissions to operate StackSets are:
{ &amp;quot;Version&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;2012-10-17&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Statement&amp;quot;: [ { &amp;quot;Effect&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Allow&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Action&amp;quot;: [ &amp;quot;cloudformation:*&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;s3:*&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;sns:*&amp;quot; ], &amp;quot;Resource&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;*&amp;quot; } ] } Having full S3, CloudFormation and SNS access cross account into production does feel like something we want to avoid.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>