<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>StackSets on Josh Armitage</title>
    <link>https://josharmi.github.io/tags/stacksets/</link>
    <description>Recent content in StackSets on Josh Armitage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://josharmi.github.io/tags/stacksets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DIY Stacksets for Terraform</title>
      <link>https://josharmi.github.io/posts/terraform-stacksets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josharmi.github.io/posts/terraform-stacksets/</guid>
      <description>What you&amp;rsquo;ll learn by the end By the end of this blog you will understand how you can build out stackset-esque functionality for your Terraform code and how this will make deploying common infrastructure across vast AWS estate significantly simpler.
Why we want Terraform stacksets Having been a heavy CloudFormation user for many years, and seeing the ecosystem of tooling that has built up around it, there was one piece I really wanted for Terraform, stacksets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIY StackSets with Step Functions</title>
      <link>https://josharmi.github.io/posts/diy-stacksets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josharmi.github.io/posts/diy-stacksets/</guid>
      <description>Why Recreate StackSets Currently in order to leverage StackSets in any way you need fairly substantial permissions in the target account, as per the documentation, the minimum permissions to operate StackSets are:
{ &amp;quot;Version&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;2012-10-17&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Statement&amp;quot;: [ { &amp;quot;Effect&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Allow&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Action&amp;quot;: [ &amp;quot;cloudformation:*&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;s3:*&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;sns:*&amp;quot; ], &amp;quot;Resource&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;*&amp;quot; } ] } Having full S3, CloudFormation and SNS access cross account into production does feel like something we want to avoid. But StackSets give us a highly efficient and useful way to deploy stacks across large swathes of the estate, how much effort is it to build something that gives us some of the same functionality with much more restricted permissions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>